# **RESUME**

HARDEEP SINGH

29, Male, Indian.

47, Link Road, Kapurthala, Punjab. hardeepkpt1@gmail.com 9803905949

\_\_\_\_\_\_

# **PROFESSIONAL OBJECTIVE**

Digital marketing person, experienced in Organic SEO, Local business SEO, SMO, SMM, ORM, AdSense, AdWords, Analytics account management and WordPress, looking forward to associating with an organization, where I can contribute and upgrade my knowledge, for development of self and organization served.

## **Education Credentials**

Standard	University/School	Year of Completion	University/Board	Percentage
M. Tech(CSE)	DAVIET, Jalandhar	2016	Punjab Technical University, Kapurthala.	69%
B. Tech(CSE)	Anand College of Engineering and Management, Kapurthala.	2014	Punjab Technical University, Kapurthala.	79.3%
DIPLOMA(CSE)	Mehar Chand Polytechnic College, Jalandhar.	2011	Punjab State Board Of Technical Education And Training, Chandigarh.	74%
10 <sup>th</sup>	Kapurthala Public High School, Kapurthala.	2008	Punjab School Education Board, Chandigarh.	74%

# Skill Set

Programming Languages	C, C++, Java.		
	Organic SEO( Advance).		
	Local SEO (Advanced).		
	Link Building (Advanced).		
Digital Marketing	WordPress (Advanced).		
	Analytics (Intermediate).		
	SMO (Intermediate).		
	AdWords (Certification in basic and mobile ads).		
	AdSense (Advanced).		
Database	SQL, MySQL (Basics).		
Operating Systems	Windows, Linux and iOS.		

#### Academic Training and Projects

- 10 Weeks of Training in August 2010 in C++ Programming
- 6 week(4 May 2012 to 16 June 2012) in Java Programming
- 6 week(4 May 2012 to 18 June 2012) in CCNA
- 6 week(May 2012 to June 2012) in Ethical Hacking
- 2 Months (June 2013 to July2013) Training to be Red Hat Certified Engineer
- 3 Months (May 2013 to July 2013) Training in Web Designing and Development in PHP
- 6 months (Jan 06, 2014 to July 4, 2014) Training in Java
- 6 months (July 2017 to December 2017) Training to be **Professional Certification in Digital Marketing**

## **Publications and Thesis**

- Published a review paper named as "Energy Efficient WSN Routing and MANET Security Techniques: A
  Review" in International Interdisciplinary Conference on Science, Technology, Engineering, Management,
  Pharmacy and Humanities held in Singapore on April 22<sup>nd</sup> 23<sup>rd</sup> 2017.
- Published a paper named as "Secure Channel Establishment Algorithm for Isolation of Selective forwarding Attack in MANET" in International Journal of Research in Electronics and Computer Engineering Vol. 5 Issue 4 October - December, 2017.
- Thesis on topic "To Evaluate and Improve AODV Protocol For Isolation of Selective Packet Forward Attack in MANET" was submitted in partial fulfillment of the requirement for the award of the degree of master in technology in computer science and engineering.

## **Work Experience**

S.No.	Designation	Time	Work Responsibilities
1	Event Blogger	March 2015 - June 2017	Website making, SEO, Adsence and more.
2	Registered Company	December 2017 to June 2018	Training Courses and Assignment Outsource.
3	Webomaze	July 2018 - March 2020	Local SEO, PPC, SMM, SMO, ORM and
	Technologies	-	more.
4	IBT Institute	December 2020- Till Date	Rank National Level and High Competitive
			Keywords

### **Work Experience Learning Details**

- **1. Event Blogger:** I have done event blogging from March 2015 to June 2017. I used to create a website on a particular event and then perform SEO tasks to get it ranked in Google and earn money by associating Google AdSense accounts with it. I gained the knowledge of the below mentioned tasks while I was working on event blogging:
- Keyword Analysis
- Competitor Analysis
- Website Design and Development
- Webmasters tools setup
- SEO( Search Engine Optimization)
  - Performing various ON page tasks
  - Performing various OFF page tasks like
- Affiliate Marketing
- Social Media Optimization
- Social Media Marketing
- Email Marketing
- 2. During Own Company: I tried to establish my own training center. I registered my own company "Digitech Web

Solutions" for this purpose. I got foreign assignment orders during this period and many SEO students. I outsourced assignments related to "Java", "Android", "Client Server Apps", "Written assignments" and more.

- **3. Webomaze Technologies**: I joined this company as "Senior SEO Analyst". I got to work on the local business promotion as well as organic projects of the clients based out in "USA", "Canada", Australia", "Germany", "UAE" and more countries. I got to learn a lot of tasks for organic and local projects.
  - 3) a) Here is the detail of tasks that I got to learn while I was working on local business promotion:
  - Creating and maintaining GMB Listing for local business promotion
  - Promotional task for GMB listing
  - Optimizing website to target local business
  - Getting links indexed using customer website or third party web 2.0 sites.
  - Recovering business from soft suspension
  - **3) b)** Apart from this, I have learned various off page tasks to generate high quality referring domains and backlinks. I have performed following new tasks while I was **working on organic projects**:
  - Paid Campaigns
  - On pages tasks
  - Off page tasks
  - Content based tasks
  - Online event creation and promotion
  - Ecommerce website SEO
  - Multilingual site SEO
  - ORM Project Handling
- **4. IBT Institute**: Joined this company as "SEO manager" right after the opening of the first lockdown in India. Here I am working on IELTS, overseas and competitive exam niche. I got to learn about:
- Amazon Product Listings
- Google News Websites
- Ranking National Level Keywords

#### Strengths

- Ability to work in a team.
- Willingness to learn new things.
- Patience and ability to manage stress.
- Ability to deal with people diplomatically.

#### Weakness

• Need improvement in mathematics.

#### **Personal Details**

Date of Birth : October 08, 1993.

Marital Status : Married Nationality : Indian

Languages Known : English, Hindi and Punjabi.

#### **Declarations**

I hereby declare that the above written particulars are true to the best of my knowledge and belief. I assure to work sincerely and prepared to do hard work duly abiding to organization.

Date: - June 21, 2023.

Place: - Kapurthala. (Hardeep Singh)